It's a bit late to ask now, but how are you feeling?
I'm fine.
Honestly, it's almost more than I can handle.
With this I feel like I could pull off ten, or even twenty projections at once.
I'm just glad it worked.
Okay, now's our chance.
Let's go.
Shirou and I will sneak into Ryuudou Temple from the rear,
and then we'll give you the signal, Saber.
When you see it, storm the temple through the front entrance
and draw his attention to you.
While you're doing that,
we'll find Shinji and the Holy Grail and shut it down.
Once that's done, all that'll be left is for you to destroy the Grail.
Look, about that...
Shirou.
There is something I must tell you first.
Saber?
I will only be able to use my holy sword once.
She has too little mana.
The instant she uses her sword, she'll vanish from this world.
What? Why?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm supplying mana to two people.
Hang on... You expect Saber to keep him busy without using her strongest attack?
Shirou...
This is my decision.
There's no other choice.
This is the only way to be sure.
Saber is my Servant.
Do you think I'd let her die for no reason?
What the hell is that?
The mana is taking physical form.
The air... It feels just like it did ten years ago.
Which means that is the Holy Grail.
The vessel must have been too small.
So the Grail's contents are trying to burst the vessel and leak out.
Burst the vessel?
In other words, Shinji.
He ought to be somewhere in there, linked to it as its core.
Could that be him up there?
I see something that looks like a person at the top.
This time, it seems the Holy Grail is using a human body to power itself.
But if this continues, the vessel's incompatibility will cause it to break apart completely.
If that happens, there won't be a Holy Grail anymore.
There'll just be that dangerous muck
oozing out of the hole opened by the Grail.
Then we have to pull Shinji out of there fast!
Wait!
You're just walking up to it unprepared?
That muck is pure curses given physical form!
We can't know if we don't try!
There's no time to lose!
Given who Saber's up against,
we don't have time for indecision.
What a surprise this is.
To think your misshapen faces would sully my vision a third time,
mongrels.
Gilgamesh!
No way! If you're here, then who is Saber fighting?!
I have been waiting.
I am glad that you arrived in time, Saber.
Assassin?
Impossible.
With Caster gone,
you should not have remained in this world!
True, but I am a unique case, you see.
I am a false Servant, summoned with this location as my anchor.
Thus I am a gatekeeper that may only appear at this main gate.
Of course,
with that vixen gone,
I shan't survive the night.
That I have managed to last this long is simply good fortune.
It appears that both you and Saber
have been forsaken by fate.
Were you unaware that a Servant who yet
lingers in this world is still at the main gate?
Assassin...
No way... He's still here?
Now, then. Simply killing you would be dull.
So I shall grant you a brief reprieve.
A reprieve?
I would feel sorry for Shinji if none but I were there at the conclusion.
Bearing witness to how this ends will give even your lives meaning.
Are you seriously planning to commit genocide against the human race?
Do you think merely putting your life on the line
entitles you to question me?
This world has become far too kind to humans.
And therein lies your answer, little girl.
This era, in which the rabble have bred to excess,
has grown far too unsightly.
What?
In the past—in my world—none were extraneous.
Even if one were a slave, one had purpose.
No matter who one was, one's life had significance.
But what of this era?
There exists more people than there is purpose and significance.
Surely you yourselves also believe that you have allowed your numbers to grow too great.
So I propose to personally cull the herd of mongrels.
The attempt ten years ago took fewer than five hundred.
But this time, disaster will rain down upon the entire world.
Once the extraneous rabble have been weeded out,
we shall find out how many people of value remain.
Does the thought not excite you?
Only a sicko like you would find that exciting!
I was a fool to expect a straight answer.
I'll put an end to your Holy Grail right now!
Tohsaka?
I'll pull Shinji out.
Whatever else he is, he's still Sakura's brother.
Besides,
isn't it your rule to save anyone as long as it's possible?
You mean to simply walk through those curses?
Do you think a lowly human could wade through that morass?
Don't underestimate me.
I can handle curses like these as if they were nothing.
Do or die, eh? How very charming.
However,
who gave you permission to leave my presence?
Tohsaka! See to Shinji!
On it!
Keep your hands off Tohsaka!
I'll take you on!
This was to be a bit of sport before I greeted Saber,
but it's proven most tedious.
You filthy sham.
Learn firsthand the difference between counterfeits and the real thing!
Stand aside, Assassin.
Surely you have no further reason to guard this gate.
Reason, you say?
In fairness, I have never had a reason to fight.
For I have neither the pride of a Heroic Spirit
nor any wish to be granted.
After all, I am not even Sasaki Kojirou.
You need not be so astonished.
At some point, a man named Sasaki Kojirou likely existed.
There was likely also a warrior who wielded a longsword named Monohoshizao.
However, those two are not the same individual.
The Sasaki Kojirou celebrated as the foil to a renowned swordsman
is but a fictional entity who never existed.
A fictional Heroic Spirit...
Indeed. "Sasaki Kojirou" is a mantle.
I was merely the swordsman deemed most suitable to wear it.
I have no name.
I am but a ghost,
summoned solely for my ability to perform the techniques that Sasaki Kojirou is said to have mastered.
Thus there was never any meaning to be found.
I am empty, so all things are meaningless for me.
However...
If there was anything even I could find meaningful,
it would be this moment.
That is, if a man who went to his death in obscurity
could have such a thing as a wish.
Assassin...
Come on...
This is just too gross!
Shit...
Learn your place, mongrel.
You will spoil the festivities.
Oh, I see it is finally time.
Boy.
Do you know what that is?
Those are wishes being drawn up by the Holy Grail.
The true nature of you mongrels.
The malevolence of humanity.
To be able to grant any and all wishes
means to effect material change upon the world
beyond the limits of what can be achieved by any living thing.
Humanity cannot grant its own wishes, for you are inherently limited beings.
Whether they are for equality, peace, or happiness,
those wishes will never be fulfilled by you, prisoners of your flesh.
That is why you humans constructed that Holy Grail—
not to be set free from all suffering
but rather to overcome it.
However, the end result of that ideal is as you see.
Nothing holds more power to change the world than the malevolent desires of humanity.
And so, fueled by malevolence, your cup of salvation can only bring about self-annihilation.
Behold your true nature.
Witness the shape an omnipotent wish-granter takes in this age.
It will be far larger in scope than ten years ago.
The curses will stream forth without end.
Now...
What will you do, boy?
Good.
This will provide me some sport.
Shinji...
Come on, time to get out of this awful place.
He may be a useless core, but you don't want to let him go?
Well, I guess anyone would be upset at having their heart yanked out.
Down we go, Shinji.
To be king is so constrictive.
The instant I take a mongrel like you seriously,
that is defeat in my eyes.
Hence, you may rejoice.
I shall not go all-out against you.
Trace...
on!
Trace on!
What's the matter?
Your quality seems to be slipping.
Is your tongue the only thing of substance about you, faker?
It's up to you...
to defeat him.
Damn it, Archer...
How am I supposed to do that?
I'm not good enough to fend off his Noble Phantasms.
There's only one thing I can do.
My only hope is to neutralize the Noble Phantasms he fires by firing back the exact same items.
So...
Trace...
I'll copy them all.
Every last one!
...on!
Possession experience, assimilation complete!
Production complete! All projections, stand by!
Oh, you're producing several this time.
I see. You have duplicated all of my
Noble Phantasms in your field of view.
Then let us score your efforts.
Of course, no matter how faithful the reproductions,
I shan't allow a single one to remain.
Release freeze...
All projections, successive fire!
Quite durable, for glasswork.
But if you don't copy faster, you'll be cut to pieces.
Trace on!
What an utterly foolish notion.
You were right to target the Holy Grail
under the assumption that you cannot beat me.
But if that is your thinking, simply killing that man would be better.
If you wish to stop the Holy Grail,
the most effective way is to eliminate Shinji.
To try to save him nonetheless is hypocrisy.
An act which sums up you mongrels perfectly.
What?
It's lost its core and now desires me as its replacement?
Tohsaka...
What the hell is that?
I can't get a read on it.
I can't even get a read on its structure!
Exterminate it,
Ea.
I thought I was holding back.
But at this rate, sparing Archer would have afforded me more amusement,
boy.
That shockwave just now...
Our positions...
Assassin, are you...
If I disengage from this man, he will use it.
His sword technique...
Is it wise to pull your blows?
If you persist, I could force you back.
Is that why you deliberately entered my range?
I have come to force an end to our contest, of course.
When in a duel, do not let your mind wander to what comes after.
If I try to put some distance between us,
I will play right into his hands.
Why do you hesitate?
Just as I guard this gate, you guard something of your own.
So there should be no room for doubt.
Besides, Saber...
You are not the only one running out of time.
I have done you a discourtesy.
As you say, we are both out of time.
Secret technique:
Swallow Reversal!
Go.
I'd thought her to be a lovely little bird,
but it seems she was closer to a lioness.
And to think I considered myself a fair judge of women.
I suppose my training in that art is equally wanting.
Only the supreme ruler may wield that blade.
Can being summoned incorrectly change a Servant so drastically?
But if I don't get there in time, do what has to be done.
Here I come, King of Heroes.
Do you have enough weapons in stock?